<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on sammyette's place</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/</link><description>Recent content in Home on sammyette's place</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 17:57:07 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sammy.is-a.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Redesigning My Website</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/website-redesign/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 17:57:07 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/website-redesign/</guid><description>Look! I redesigned my website. No longer will my blog and home page look completely different.
Starting from yesterday, I have moved my website from being a plain GitHub pages site written in just HTML to Hugo, which I also use for my blogs. This means that I now have both my blog content and my site content in one place, and that they look exactly the same.
But why? Because I wanted to.</description></item><item><title>Lite XL - A dream close to reality</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/lite-xl/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 23:58:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/lite-xl/</guid><description>A text editor is one of the programs I spend the most time in, since in my free time I&amp;rsquo;m working on a code project. Having a comfortable, extensible text editor is important to me.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been happily using Neovim for the past 1-2 years by now. Before that, while on Windows, I was using Sublime Text around 3 years ago. Back then, I just needed something to code in with some kind of autocomplete.</description></item><item><title>Please Make Your APIs Restful</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/please-make-your-apis-restful/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 22:33:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/please-make-your-apis-restful/</guid><description>Have you ever been working on something but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work properly and you don&amp;rsquo;t know why? This is exactly what I thought when I was working on Circleload yesterday.
It&amp;rsquo;s a tool that downloads osu! beatmaps from unofficial mirrors. One of them was Kitsu (not the anime list) that looked really simple. Except when it returned status code 200 for a beatmap I know doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist.
Turns out that this API, when getting a beatmap, returns an object like this:</description></item><item><title>Efficiency</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/efficiency/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 21:26:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/efficiency/</guid><description>Usually I try to be as efficient as possible when doing things. I also like having certain ways to organize and do things. A simple example is bread. I make sure to cut the bread, toast the bread and put it back together properly.
Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to work on my Neovim config so that I can be more efficient with certain things. I setup the new LSP and completions stuff and even added a keybind to toggle a terminal buffer so I only ever have 1 actual terminal window open at all times, though I have to make a less dumb keybind to exit terminal mode, ctrl + \ and ctrl + n is very annoying.</description></item><item><title>Software Names</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/software-names/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 10:06:58 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/software-names/</guid><description>Naming things is hard, especially new projects and software. I like flowers. They&amp;rsquo;re pretty and nice so if I&amp;rsquo;m lazy, I just name a new piece of my software based on a flower that I like. But I don&amp;rsquo;t just pick any flower. I gotta have a unique sounding name and I also can&amp;rsquo;t just name the repo &amp;ldquo;NightSkyPetunia&amp;rdquo; so I&amp;rsquo;m limited to a short single word name.
Other times I do actually take effort in thinking of a name based on what it is about, or thing of a random name and just theme the project based on it.</description></item><item><title>Terminal Emulators</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/terminal-emulators/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 23:43:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/terminal-emulators/</guid><description>Yesterday I decided to make a custom status line for my Neovim config. In the status line there is a section between the git status and diff indicator and the percentage of where I am in the buffer. I thought the space between the two looked a tiny bit too much, so with my high intelligence I used a smaller unicode block character. It solved my problem, except with Alacritty (the terminal I use) there was a tiny piece sticking out from the line.</description></item><item><title>Switching from Spotify to Local Music</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/switching-from-spotify-to-local-music/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 21:06:15 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/switching-from-spotify-to-local-music/</guid><description>As I mentioned in one of my posts before, I like listening to music. Who doesn&amp;rsquo;t? I have it in the background while working on a project, I jam to it while bored or just have it playing so my environment won&amp;rsquo;t be completely silent. Except when you get interrupted by an ad.
Spotify, and others like YouTube Music or Deezer are all pretty cool, but they have ads (besides YT) unless you pay for a monthly subscription service.</description></item><item><title>Emptiness</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/emptiness/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 12:37:04 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/emptiness/</guid><description>A lot of people wish that they could have free time to do whatever they want, that being playing some games or catching up on a TV series. On the other hand, I wish that I could be occupied with more things.
Since I am still a student, having to deal with a few online classes in the week, I have a lot of free time to code things or play games.</description></item><item><title>Organization &amp; Scheduling</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/scheduling/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 23:07:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/scheduling/</guid><description>For the most part, I try to be as organized as possible. There&amp;rsquo;s times where I just don&amp;rsquo;t bother at all, but the way that I layout my things are pretty organized. Despite this, I actually don&amp;rsquo;t have a formal schedule for myself. I do have some sort of routine of course, but I&amp;rsquo;ll do things during the day at pretty much any time.
A friend of mine is very scheduled on their anime watching.</description></item><item><title>Productivity</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/productivity/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 21:10:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/productivity/</guid><description>I like looking at statistics sometimes. Charts, graphs or whatever, they look nice. This is why I semi-frequently look at my Wakatime dashboard. Wakatime has actually made me a bit more productive.
I set a daily goal of coding 4 hours or more everyday. The only times I can take a break on this is when I don&amp;rsquo;t code in the day at all, like just to chill on Discord or watch a kdrama.</description></item><item><title>Kdramas</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/kdramas/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 19:22:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/kdramas/</guid><description>Good entertainment for me is thrilling (melo)drama. I mentioned in one of my previous posts that I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching What&amp;rsquo;s Wrong with Secretary Kim? and it&amp;rsquo;s a romance drama. I still haven&amp;rsquo;t finished watching it yet, because I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing posts for this blog and playing retro games.
A show that I have been keeping up with is The Second Husband. It&amp;rsquo;s episode length is 30mins so it&amp;rsquo;s easier to digest but has 120 episodes total.</description></item><item><title>Why I Like Kpop (and other non-English music)</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/why-i-like-kpop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 19:36:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/why-i-like-kpop/</guid><description>I like listening to music, it&amp;rsquo;s easy and accessible. Unlike video media where I have to actually pay attention, I can play music in the background and jam out. What type of music do I listen to? I listen to what sounds good to me. But I do have specific genres I like, one of them being kpop.
Immediate reaction for the average person (when you read the title) is that &amp;ldquo;kpop bad, not good music u dont even understand what theyre saying.</description></item><item><title>Fostering a Discord Community</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/fostering-a-discord-community/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 18:25:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/fostering-a-discord-community/</guid><description>I like owning and managing Discord communities. I enjoy bringing people together and making a hub for people to chat. I&amp;rsquo;ve moderated a few Discord servers before, and even owned one myself with 500 members.
Even though in real life I am very introverted and not that social, in the online world I kinda like talking to people (with similar interests of course) which is why I enjoy managing servers, since staff members would be the ones with most interaction with the community at large.</description></item><item><title>Motivation and Self-esteem</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/motivation-and-self-esteem/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 09:23:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/motivation-and-self-esteem/</guid><description>I sometimes wonder how people keep motivated to work on projects or do certain things. I&amp;rsquo;m basically just a hobbyist software developer who&amp;rsquo;s not that well known. Motivation to do things has been the only problem for me for the past few months or even the (year).
Hilbish is my biggest project, which is just a simple shell stitched together with Lua and a sh interpreter with an API. The only reason I am keeping it updated for the most part is because I personally use Hilbish.</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/introduction/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 07:30:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/introduction/</guid><description>I feel like I should make a more general introduction post to tell more info about myself. Hello!
I&amp;rsquo;m sammyette, if you couldn&amp;rsquo;t tell. Some people just call me sammy since it&amp;rsquo;s easier, or TorchedSammy as that&amp;rsquo;s my username in some places (kinda want to change though). I write code. It&amp;rsquo;s not good code at all, but it works and lately that is all that I care about.
Besides programming dumb things, I also watch TV shows like dramas and anime.</description></item><item><title>Making a Blog</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/making-a-blog/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 22:35:44 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/blog/making-a-blog/</guid><description>Hello, sammy here. A blog!
I decided to make a blog so I can put some of my random thoughts or do a write up on something. Why? Why not?
It&amp;rsquo;ll probably be boring and kinda inactive but whatever.
If you couldn&amp;rsquo;t notice, it&amp;rsquo;s made with Hugo since I thought that would be the easiest to setup. I previously had my thoughts up over here on tilde.town but this is easier to theme in my opinion.</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>https://sammy.is-a.dev/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sammy.is-a.dev/projects/</guid><description>coming soon</description></item></channel></rss>